Ludmila Korchnoy

Miami, FL | 845-641-6836 | <u>Ludmilakorchnoy@gmail.com</u> <u>GitHub</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Blog</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for creativity, innovation and solving problems through analytics. With experience in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React and a background in management, marketing and customer service, my interest in programming began when I created a website focused on startups in the tech industry. I bring strong skills in organization and attention to detail. As an effective communicator, I am able to facilitate a cohesive work environment that promotes collaboration.

SKILLS

Technical: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, JavaScript, React, Redux, Redux Thunk, CRUD, REST API, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), MVC frameworks, Github, Mode Analytics, SQL, HTML5, CSS

Languages: Fluent in Russian

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Ordinary-Startups GitHub | Demo

App features disrupt startups with avant-garde concepts and high technology that provide easy solutions for everyday tasks.

- Utilized Ruby on Rails and the MVC pattern to design the app
- Leveraged bcrypt to facilitate custom authentication and OmniAuth to provide third party authentication
- Designed the database schema and configured ActiveRecord associations
- Incorporated nested forms, nested routes, and validations

Perfect Plant GitHub | Demo

This app is based on a personality test which suggests the perfect indoor plant for every type of personality.

- Deployed ES6 JavaScript frontend and Ruby on Rails API backend to offer responsive website SPA layout
- Applied AJAX Fetch requests to rails API sent by frontend JavaScript to handle client-server communication
- Developed Rails API backend to handle data persistence and respond to Fetch requests
- Styled frontend with Bootstrap and custom CSS

Free Time GitHub | Demo

App for creating and sharing music videos.

- Utilized React and Redux client-side for an interactive, efficient UI with unidirectional data flow
- Built Rails backend with API endpoints for Fetch requests
- Leveraged Redux Thunk middleware to respond to and modify state changes
- Created client-side routing using React router and RESTful routing
- Styled frontend with custom CSS

EXPERIENCE

Franck Muller Watchland SA, New York, NY

02/2007 - 04/2011 03/2009 - 04/2011

Boutique Manager

- Oversaw all in-house logistical operations
- Supervised and managed store employees
- Implemented various marketing and selling strategies
- Created productivity reports for store employees
- Developed procedures for the sales staff that provided clients with a high-end customer experience

Sales Associate 02/2007 - 03/2009

- Promoted the new company store and introduced new timepieces to customers
- Provided customer service

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY

12/2019 -10/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Ramapo College, Mahwah, NJ

Bachelor of Science, Biology